Matt Fletcher

Full Stack Developer



mattfletcher94@outlook.com



\(\sqrt{} 07512816449



mattfletcher.name



Plymouth, UK

Self-motivated full stack developer with a Computer Science degree (First Class Honours) and over three years industry experience. Penchant for UX and developing modern web applications that factor in unique demands for flexibility, accessibility and security. Proficient in fundamental front-end and server-side languages, with in-depth knowledge of Vue, React, Express, MongoDB and SQL. Familiar with working in fast-paced and high pressured environments, requiring fast turnaround. Eager to contribute to the team's success through hard work, attention to detail, and strong motivations to exceed expectations.



Skills

The essentials such as HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Typescript, OOP, SOLID are implied from the listed skills.

Vue / Nuxt	
React / Next	
WordPress	00000
Node / Express	
API Development	
SQL / MongoDB	
UI/UX	
Agile	
Dev Ops	



Work History

@Pitched Ltd 2019 - Current

Full Stack Developer

 Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to build over 20 custom themes with intuitive back offices and modern front-ends, viewed by thousands of visitors daily. Including a SaaS product with over 15 paid subscribers.

- Introduced and encouraged Pitched to utilize modern web technologies and methodologies such as React, Vue, Tailwind and Test Driven Development.
- Developed component libraries and web applications using React, Next or Vue; with user authentication, API integration and strong emphasis on UX.
- Designed and Developed their self-sign-up process for their booking system, increasing their online enrolment.

@Self-employed2016 – Current

Web Developer

- Converted design assets into customizable WordPress themes, while adhering to SEO best practices.
- Translated customer requirements into technical site concepts before developing sites with required technologies.
- Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.
- Regularly organized meetings with clients to ensure their website would exceed their expectations.



Education

2017 - 2021 BSc Computer Science at Plymouth University

Graduated with a First Class Honors.

2014 - 2016 BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma: Music Technology

Grade: DMM.